<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Design on dranet</title><link>https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/</link><description>Recent content in Design on dranet</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 11:20:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RDMA</title><link>https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/rdma/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 11:20:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/rdma/</guid><description>Understanding RDMA Components in Linux RDMA (Remote Direct Memory Access) is a powerful technology enabling applications to directly read from or write to memory on a remote machine without involving the CPU, caches, or operating system of either machine during the data transfer. This achieves ultra-low latency and high throughput, making it ideal for high-performance computing (HPC), AI/ML, and storage.
In a Linux system, the RDMA ecosystem involves several interconnected components:</description></item><item><title>How It Works</title><link>https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/howitworks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:20:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/howitworks/</guid><description>The networking DRA driver uses GRPC to communicate with the Kubelet via the DRA API and the Container Runtime via NRI. This architecture facilitates the supportability and reduces the complexity of the solution, it also makes it fully compatible and agnostic of the existing CNI plugins in the cluster.
The DRA driver, once the Pod network namespaces has been created, will receive a GRPC call from the Container Runtime via NRI to execute the corresponding configuration.</description></item><item><title>References</title><link>https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/references/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 11:20:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://google.github.io/dranet/docs/concepts/references/</guid><description> KEP 3063 - Dynamic Resource Allocation #306 KEP 3695 - DRA: structured parameters #438 Extend PodResources to include resources from Dynamic Resource Allocation (DRA) Working Group Device Management Kubernetes Network Drivers, Antonio Ojea, Presentation The Future of Kubernetes Networking - Antonio Ojea, Googe &amp;amp; Dan Winship, Red Hat - Kubernetes Contributor Summit EU 2024 Better Together! GPU, TPU and NIC Topological Alignment with DRA - John Belamaric, Google &amp;amp; Patrick Ohly, Intel - Kubecon US 2024</description></item></channel></rss>